[SPEAKER_00]: Bhikkhus, this saṃsāra is without a knowable beginning.
[SPEAKER_00]: A first point is not discerned of beings roaming and wandering on, obscured by ignorance and bound by craving.
[SPEAKER_00]: What do you think, bhikkhus, which is more?
[SPEAKER_00]: The water in the four great oceans, or the flow of the blood that you have shed when your head was chopped off, while roaming and wandering on through this long course?
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they reply, venerable sir, as we understand the dhamma taught by the blessed one, the flow of the blood that we have shed when our head was chopped off while roaming and wandering on, this alone is more than all the water in the four great oceans.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good, good bhikkhus.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's good that you understand my teaching in this way.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he goes on.
[SPEAKER_00]: For a long time, you've been cows.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the flow of blood you've shed when your head was chopped off as a cow is more than all the water in the four great oceans.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then, for a long time, you've been buffalo, rams, goats, sheeps, chicken, pigs.
[SPEAKER_00]: For a long time, you've been bandits, arrested for raiding villages, highway robbery or adultery.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the flow of blood you've shed when you were beheaded as a bandit is more than all the water in the four great oceans.